Guide to the Robert Nelson Bush Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, 23 box(es)
  - Reports, articles, speeches, and other miscellaneous items, primarily by Bush
    - "Self Determination and Self Regulation in the Profession of Teaching" (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "American Educational Needs in the 70's: Implications for Federal Policies and Actions" December 12, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - " A Memo to the Commission" January, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "The Science and Art of Educating Teachers" October 22,23, 1965 @ Phi Delta Kappa Meeting, Stanford, CA (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - AACTE Staff Development Workshop: The Real World of the Organizational Life of the School, Jan. 15-17, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Theory Into Practice: "Teachers We Need" April, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Book, The Role of the Teacher, p 13 "Teaching: The Formative Years" (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - SCRDT Memo #47, "The Status of the Career Teacher: Its Effect upon the Teacher Drop-Out Problem" 1969,70 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - A Position Paper: Teacher Education and Professional Standards R. Bush 1967 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Outline of Speech for SCRDT 10th Anniversary & Summary of Event (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Article for Scottish Ed Journal "The Current Status of Education in the US" July 8, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Testimony before Open Committee Hearing of the Commission for Teacher Preparation and Licensing of the State of CA October 28,1971 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Phi Delta Kappan Jan. 1965 Vol. XLVI #5, page 244 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - General Session Address, June 22, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - The CA Journal of Secondary Education October 1957, Editorial (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Alumni News Letter March 1946 Vol. 3, #5 Stanford U, School of Ed. (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Outline of a Presentation to West HS. Faculty Denver Colorado 12/14/42 "Education and the War" (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Outline of Opening Remarks to Students and Faculty at the Opening Convocation of the 78th year of the KSTC of Emporia, Kansas 9/13/43 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Preliminary Proposal for Community Organization and Personnel Training Program Designed to Meet the Needs for Conversion to a Peace Time Economy, December, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - The Education Digest: Teacher Education For the Future, Nov., 1975 p44 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Occasional Paper #1: Educational Research and Development: A New Force March 1975 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Occasional Paper #4: A Special School for Teacher Ed?, June 1975 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Occasional Paper #11: Educational Research and Development: The Next Decade, June 1976 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Occasional Paper #12: Educational Research and Public Policy: Problems and Promise, June 1976 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - The Bulletin of the National Association of Secondary School Principals, May 1963 "Flexible Scheduling" p 73 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Journal of Research and Development in Education Summer 1968, "Center for Research and Development in Teaching" p. 87 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Educational Leadership, January 1961 "The Problem of A Flexible Schedule in High School," p 205 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - The Bulletin of the National Association of Secondary School Principals Apr. 1964: Decision for the Principal: Hand or Computer Scheduling? p. 141 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Democracy vs. Dictatorship "Teaching Aids," p 45 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - The Australian Journal of Education, April, 1958 "The Teacher-Pupil Relationship" p. 41 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Journal of Secondary Education Editorials: October 1962, December 1962 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Journal of Secondary Education R. Bush Editorials; 1956-1962 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - A New Design for High School Education: Assuming a Flexible Schedule, RN Bush, 1964 [book] (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - A New Design for High School Education: Assuming a Flexible Schedule, July 1961 [Preliminary Draft] (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Teacher Education: A Reappraisal, 1962 p. 183 " A Schema for Teacher Education" (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Audio-visual materials
    - Audio Tape: Dr. Bush--Run through of Presentation for Tuesday Evening Lecture Series, March 11,1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Slides, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Professor Robert Bush--Rotary: Mon., Nov., 26, 1973; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Perspective II-- "Schools in Transition" Dr. Robert Bush, Dr. Michael Kirst, January 17, 1984; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Film: Original KANKAKEE Urban/ Rural Film 8/1/76 RN Bush (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Audio Recording: Ed. 343--Dr. Bush Class--Thursday Oct. 19, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Bush--GSO, April 11, 1973; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Card files (Box 20)
    - Address file (on 3 x 5 cards) (Box 20)
    - Bush's bibliography through 1967 (on 3 x 5 cards) (Box 20)
  - Notes from a consulting trip to Australia in 1956 (Box 21)
    - Notes from consulting trip to Australia 1956 and an "eastern trip" 1957 (Box 21)
  - Class materials for education 219 (Box 22-23)
    - Education 219, Group II, General Seminar minutes, October 1960 - June 1961 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Education 219, Compiled summary of materials used for Education 219, Part III Complete, Autumn 1961 - Winter 1963 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Education 219, Compiled summary of materials used for Education 219, Part IV Complete, Spring-Summer 1963 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Education 219, November 9, 1963; Introductory materials for the Analysis and Interpretation of Sociometric Data (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-061; 1 box(es)
  - Report on the SCRDT office design, 1971 (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2008-059; 1 box(es)
  - Black, Richard and Elizabeth Huidekoper, "Financial Aid at Harvard," 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clarke, S.C.T., "Designs for Programs of Teacher Education," 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Delta News-Journal (Delta Campus Chapter, Phi Delta Kappa, SU) Dec. 1965 [on the Symposium on Teacher Education held at SU Oct. 1965] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Final Report of the Task Force on Teacher Education, submitted to the School of Education, Stanford University, March 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Huff, Robert P., two papers on need analysis systems in student aid, 1972, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hurd, Paul DeHart, "A Brief History of the NSF Science Curriculum Improvement Projects," September 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1968-78 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nelson, James E. "The Role of the College Scholarship Service," April 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NSF, Science and Engineering Education Directorate, "Program Funding History: 1952-1985" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Policy Statement Teacher Corps Youth Advocacy Program, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Shaftel, Fannie R. "The Stanford Evaluation of Nine Elementary Teacher Training Models," 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - SCRDT publication list, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student assistance, various papers on, 1977-84 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Testimony of Donald Kennedy at Field Hearing on The Impact of the Administration's Budget Cuts, U. S. House of Representatives, Jan.18, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2009-174; 2 box(es)
  - Urban / Rural school development program files
    - General background and report, 1969-71 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - First National Conference, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - correspondence, 1973-77 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - News clippings 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Phase II, Original notes - planning (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Phase II, proposal to Office of Education, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Phase II, planning meeting, Washington, DC, May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Phase II, planning meeting, Washington, DC, Feb. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Phase II, Year II, negotiation, Washington, April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Phase II, planning meeting, Washington, DC, Sept. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Phase II, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Site chronologies and narratives, 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Proposals, contracts, 1973-76 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Published documents 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - General 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Commission for Teacher Preparation and Licensing
    - Correspondence, agenda, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, agenda, reports, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Work by others
    - Final Report, Center for Interracial Cooperation, Principal Investigator: Elizabeth G. Cohen (SUSE), no date (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Environment for Teaching Program, SCRDT: 2 papers on "Organizational Support for Innovative Instructional Programs" for the Annual Meeting of the American Educational Research Association, April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Warren, Richard L. "Teacher Encounters: a typology for ethnographic research on the teaching experience," 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dornbusch, et. al. "The Collegial Evaluation Program: A Manual for the Professional Development of Teachers," 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Cohen, Elizabeth, 2 papers: Teachers and Specialists, 1977 and Modifying Status Relations in Israel Youth, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Haskew, Lawrence D., 2 papers: Remarks, Oct. 25, 1967 and Impact of the Research upon the Practice of Teacher Education, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Sam J. Yarger, Ken Howey, and Bruce Joyce – 3 papers (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Collier, Raymond O., Some Strengths and Weaknesses of Research Methodology in Teacher Education, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Peck, Robert F., Personalizing and Individualizing Education: A Progress Report, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Donovan, Bernard E., The Teachers We Need, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Biddle, Bruce J., Recent Research in Classroom Behavior, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - McDonald, Frederick J., Research on Learning in School Settings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - E. Rattner and J. Aldrich, Characteristics of Teaching Training Institutions, Part I, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Sarason, Seymour, The Preparation of Teachers: Still Unstudied, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Haberman, Martin, Suggestions for Recruiting, Developing, and Evaluating the National Teacher Corps, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - B. Othanel Smith and Milton Meux, Research in Teacher Education: Problems, Analysis, and Criticism, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Dorothy S. Blackmore, et. al., The Granada Plan, An approach to new horizons of individualized teacher competence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Statement by Edson W. Sample, President National Association of Student Financial Aid Administrators, before the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education of the House Education and Labor Committee, March 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - National Inservice Teacher Education Study, [survey results for California], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - RESTRICTED FILES
    - Garfield, Gary (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hau, Liz (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Huguenin, Kathy (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Joyce, Bruce (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Joyce, Bruce (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Manriquez, Bert (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Mesa, Pete (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Moore, Helen (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Nur, Mary (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Phelan, Pat (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Shepherd, Pat (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Sibilla, Susan (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ware, Ken (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2012-041; 3 box(es)
  - accreditation, 1963-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - bibliographies, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Beginning Teacher Evaluation Study (BTES), 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5-11)
  - competence, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conant, James B., 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Educational Coordinates, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - scheduling, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Teacher Corps, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18-26)
  - teacher education: miscellaneous papers, notes, 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Urban/Rural Leadership Training Institute, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 28-38)
  - RESTRICTED: Urban/Rural Leadership Training Institute, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Commission for Teacher Preparation and Licensing, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1-16)
  - RNB to Conant/Educational Training Service, 1963-12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Education USA, 1964-10 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - College Student Personnel abstracts, 1965-03 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - DeLay/Allen "A Continuous Monitor... ", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Symposium on Educational Manpower "What We Don't Know About Educational Manpower", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NEA National Committee on Teacher Education and Study: The Year of the Non-Conference, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford School of Education Futures Report, 1971-06 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kirst "Issues in Governance... ", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - RNB "Educational Research and Public Policy" SCRDT, 1976-06 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NEA/AFT Forum, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Goldhammer "Premises and Problems of Collegiate-Based Educational Personnel Development Programs", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mitzell "Increasing the Impact of Theory... ", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cohen et. al. "Principal Role and Teacher Morale... " SCRDT, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - National Council on Education Research "Fundamental Research... ", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - NEA Project on Utilization of Inservice Education R+D Outcomes, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ogunbi "Perceived Relevance of Foreign Students' Training... ", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - RNB Rotary Speech notes, 1978-11 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Best of ERIC, 1979-04 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - RNB "The Beginning Years of Teaching", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Maidment "Straight Talk", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Shavelson "Research on Teachers' Pedagogical Thoughts... ", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sacramento Bee clippings re: extension programs and teacher salary, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - National Agenda for The Eighties (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Webster "Some Thoughts on Restructuring California's Credential System", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gage and Giaconia "Teaching Practices... ", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - National Council on Educational Research report, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Fetterman "Ethnography in Educational Research", 1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Civic Learning for Teachers Seminar Proceedings, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)